Mikayla Zwerdling - New York, NY zwerdlingmikavla@gmail.com

Portfolio - mikaylazwerdling.com

linkedin.com/in/mikayla-zwerdling/

864-631-7180

Graphic Designer - Typography - Web Design - Branding - Video Production

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

I have over 5 years of experience and intense educational instruction in visual arts and graphic design, gained while working at a Global Career Coaching and Outplacement firm along with a Global Staffing and Recruiting firm. I have extensive expertise in Typographic Design, Advertising and Branding, Experimental Print Design, 2D and 3D Animation, Adobe Suite (Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, Premiere Pro, Lightroom, After Effects), Kinetic Typography, Logo Design, HTML and CSS, Corporate PowerPoint Presentation Development, and Video Production.

Here is a link to my portfolio http://mikaylazwerdling.com

In addition, I have gained a comprehensive education and instruction while attending the Parsons School of Design at the New School, the Governor's School for the Arts and Humanities residential High School, and the Maryland Institute College of Art "MICA" (pre-college) Program. I have over 5 years of work experience in creating and editing corporate PowerPoint presentations, banner ads, logo design, web pages, whitepapers, eBooks and video production. I also received a National Silver Medal in Design from Scholastic Art and Writing.

I am currently studying graphic design at the Parsons School of Design at The New School in New York City (Completed Sophomore year - Class of 2022).

Graphic Design Expertise

- Typography
- Adobe Suite (Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, Premiere Pro, Lightroom, After Effects)
- Advertising and Branding
- Print/Book Design
- Experimental Typography

- Web Design, HTML and CSS
- Kinetic Typography
- Logo Design
- Corporate PowerPoint Presentation Development
- Video Production

Technical/Software Proficiencies

Adobe Suite (Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, Premiere Pro, Lightroom, After Effects), Figma, Sketch, HTML and CSS, DragonFrame, PowerPoint, MS Word, Excel, Google Docs

CAREER EXPERIENCE

Global Expansion, Inc. Greenville, SC

7/2018 - Present

Freelance Graphic Designer for Global Staffing, Human Resources and Career Coaching Company

- Created and managed visual media print, web and video.
- Layout and design of whitepapers and eBooks, brochures and marketing collateral.
- Logo design, website banner ads, business cards.
- Designed and managed PowerPoint marketing presentations for company services.

Foreign Staffing, Inc. Greenville, SC 1/2014 - 12/2016

Freelance Graphic Designer for International Staffing and Payroll Company

- Created and managed visual media print and web.
- Directed and produced 12 educational videos for company's website and YouTube channel.
- Designed and managed PowerPoint marketing services presentations, whitepapers, eBooks & banner ads.

AG Jeans New York, NY

3/2019 - 7/2019

Retail Sales Associate for AG Jeans Hudson Yards

AG Jeans (Adriano Goldschmied) is an exclusively premium, socially active, and responsible denim brand. Creates, manages, and develops customer relations using knowledge of the brand, strong sales strategies and high levels of customer service.

- Established and maintained a solid understanding of the company Point of Sale System in order to efficiently process customer and store transactions.
- Maintained a clean and well merchandised store environment that consistently met company standards.
- Protected company assets by following all loss prevention procedures.
- Maintained a high level of PK (product knowledge) by staying current with supplied product knowledge tools and seasonal look books.
- Consistently exceeded monthly Individual Sales Plans.

Parsons School of Design - Open Campus - New York, NY 9/2018 - 12/2018

Pre-College Teaching Assistant

- Instructor of Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop to New York City High School Students.
- Taught basic type design and photo manipulation, contributed to critiques, gave ideas and helped expand student concepts.

EDUCATION:

Parsons School of Design at the New School - New York, NY 8/2018 - Present (Class of 2022)

A private art and design college located in the Greenwich Village neighborhood of Lower Manhattan.

Coursework: Major - Graphic Design

- Web Design and Development
- Interaction Design
- Fashion Editorial Design
- Narrative Film and Editing
- Drawing/Imaging
- Space/Materiality

- Creative Coding (html, css, javascript)
- Advanced Typography
- Sustainability and Design
- Typographic History
- Intro to Japanese

The South Carolina Governor's School for the Arts & Humanities - Greenville, SC 8/2016 - 5/2018 - GPA (4.5)

Nationally recognized, pre-professional residential arts and academic high school. Students live on campus in a safe and structured environment which allows them to truly become immersed in their art discipline and their studies. Students gain experience preparing portfolios, exhibiting artwork in regional exhibitions, and entering local and national competitions.

Governor's School Coursework:

Graphic Design

- Branding
- Experimental Typography
- Font Design
- Poster Design
- Advertising

2D Design/Drawing

- Printmaking
- Painting
- Life Drawing

Animation

- Motion Graphics
- Stop Motion
- Kinetic Typography
- Hand Drawn

3D Design

- Functional Ceramics
- Metalworking
- Architecture
- Sculpture

Maryland Institute College of Art "MICA" (Pre-college) Program, Baltimore, MD Summer 2017

Acknowledged nationally as a premier leader in art and design education, MICA is deliberately cultivating a new generation of artists.

• Studied Animation and Graphic Design in Summer 2017 Intensive Program

MISCELLANEOUS:

- Member of Girl Scouts 2006 2018
- South Carolina Governor's School for the Arts & Humanities
 - o Film Club September 2016 May 2018
 - o Created and Distributed Promotional Materials for Club screenings
- Yearbook Staff September 2017 May 2018
 - Developed page spread layouts for school wide yearbook
- City of Greenville March For Our Lives Against Gun Violence Designed Event Poster
- Scholastic Art & Writing Awards, the nation's longest running and most prestigious scholarship and recognition initiative for creative teens
 - o National Silver Medal in Design 2018
 - o 2 Regional Gold Keys, 2 Regional Silver Keys, Honorable Mention
- 28th Annual Upstate High School Art Exhibit
 1st Place Graphic Design, 2018
- All American High School Film Festival Official 2018 Selection
 Short Film Experimental Kinetic Typography

Check Out My Portfolio -

mikaylazwerdling.com